

Eva Tinka

A Psychologist and Wellbeing Coach in Health City

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: info@healthcity.org.uk/ Website: https://healthcity.org.uk/

Personal profile

I am a Psychology Coach, with extensive experience in healthcare. I am a trained Cousellor and a Psychologist with Graduate Basis for Chartered Membership with the British Psychological Society.

As a Coach I use my knowledge, skill, expertise, experience and a creative approach to help people and organisations (with a wide range of problematic situations) to unlock their full potential and be catapulted from where they are stuck to where they want to be.

I use Psychology and Coaching tools to tailor sessions to individual Clients and their needs. My main areas of specialism are Confidence, Resilience and Well being. I use CBT to help clients with Stress, depressions and other Psychological Problems.

Work Experience

- Head of Staff Wellbeing and Engagement Head of Staff Wellbeing and Engagement, Whittington NHS Trust, Health Service, United Kingdom. · Full-time. Oct 2023 – Present.
- Psychology Coach and Partner Psychology, Health City, Mental Health Services. Health City, March 2018 – Present. London, United Kingdom.
- Director, Eden Tailored Coaching, 2015 Present, London, United Kingdom.
 - Offering Coaching Services to Individuals Families and organisations
- Wellbeing Lead, Barts Health NHS Trust · Full-time, Barts Health NHS Trust, Feb 2023 - Oct 2023, London, England, United Kingdom.
- Wellbeing Lead Wellbeing Lead, East Kent Hospitals University NHS Foundation Trust. · Full-time, Sep 2021 - Mar 2023, Kent, United Kingdom.

- Biomedical Scientist, NHS, Dec 2004 Sep 2021, London, United Kingdom.
 - My responsibilities include diagnosis of infection through the identification of a range of Microorganisms (bacteria, fungi, parasites and Viruses), training Medical Laboratory Technicians, Biomedical Scientists and some Doctors on rotation. I also write quality control documents that adhere to ISO (International Organization for Standardization) standards in preparing the laboratory for ISO accreditation and subsequent maintenance of this accreditation.
 - Biomedical Scientist, Department of infection, St Thomas' Hospital (2006- Sep 2021): I gained multidisciplinary experience, working in Virology and Microbiology, diagnosing a range of infections such as TB, HIV, Gonorrhea, Swine flu, etc. Aside the diagnostic and analytical work, I gained great customer awareness skills. I liaise with the doctors about patients with unusual laboratory results. In addition, I supervise a team of laboratory assistants.
 - Biomedical Scientist, Microbiology department, Hammersmith hospital: Working as a fully qualified state registered biomedical scientist, I professionally applied the skills acquired during my traineeship, to diagnose infections.
- Trustee and Chair of Governors, The Woodland Academy Trust, Jan 2012 - Aug 2018, Erith, United Kingdom.
- Psycho-Social Therapist, CRI, 2011 2012, London, United Kingdom.
 - Providing Counselling to Individuals and Facilitating group counselling sessions, using CBT (Cognitive Behavioural Therapy) as the main treatment modality.
- Assistant Psychologist: CRI (Crime Reduction Initiative) and Sussex NHS Partnership Trust 11/2010-08/2011. Following a well structured comprehensive training in addiction and psychological services I went on to gain immense and varied experience of psychological services within the Voluntary sector and NHS partnership. I acquired a lot of client contact, ranging from one-to-one contact to group work. I applied psychological theory and knowledge to assist clients with a range of mental health issues and processes (e.g. anxiety, depression, guilt, shame) in order to combat their drug addiction. I skilled up and was able to run my client caseload autonomously from managing appointments, conducting psychological needs assessments, formulation, treatment and evaluation. Following a few sessions co-facilitating the cocaine and alcohol group I was able to confidently and successfully facilitate the group for a full cycle of 8 sessions. A number of my clients showed a good success rate in combating their drug use and returned to employment. I

gained knowledge and experience in, using the electronic system for data logging, Key-working, home visits and writing formal documents such as official letters and Psychology reports. My ability to be a reflective practitioner has significantly improved as a result of attending fortnightly supervision with a Clinical psychologist.

- Assistant Psychologist, Lewisham addiction psychology services, South London & Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust (01/2010-08/2010):

 I gained tremendous insight and experience in psychology services from working as a voluntary psychology assistant at the Lewisham addiction psychology service. I gained an overall insight in the provision of Psychological services within the NHS from referral to treatment and discharge of clients. Aside sitting in on numerous assessment sessions, I was trained to complete a range of assessment forms such as the Treatment outcome Profiles (TOP), Risk assessments forms, initial contact forms etc.
- Telephone interviewer, National Opinion Polls in Wimbledon & Synovate in Kennington: Working in market research as a telephone interviewer, I applied my verbal communication skills and my friendly yet assertive manner to persuade people to take part in surveys and secure interviews. I successfully worked under pressure to meet set targets and deadlines. I used my charisma to maintain customers' interest throughout very long interviews.

Education

2009- University of East London, UK.

MSc Psychology, Merit

Modules Studied: Cognitive Psychology, Research methods, Psychobiology, Social Psychology, Individual differences, Developmental psychology and Conceptual historical issues in Psychology

2000 – 2004 University of Hull, UK.

BSc Biomedical Science with Honours, 2.1

Modules studied: Medical microbiology, Clinical Chemistry, Haematology, Cellular pathology, Cytology, IT skills, Numerical techniques, Management in the NHS, Molecular Genetics, Biotechnology, social and Psychology.

1997 - 2000 Saint Francis Xavier College, London

BTEC National Diploma in Science, Distinction

1993 –1997 Southfield's Community College, London

GCSEs: 6 B's and 3 C's

Achievements: I have successfully counseled clients to manage their mental health problems and triggers and consequently combat their drug abuse and live their desired way of life.

I was awarded the overall student of the year, Saint Francis Xavier College 2000.

As publicity lead, I was able to revive a failing Afro-Carribean society by increasing number of members, securing local business sponsorships, increasing the overall reputation of the society and profit.

Hobbies & Interests

- I enjoy socialising with and entertaining friends.
- I love to learn about different cultures thus I have friends from many different cultures.
- Reading and dancing

References on request.